Guide to the Liberty Hyde Bailey papers, 1845-2004
Bailey, Liberty Hyde papers, 1845-2004
- Series VII. Writings
  - Mostly published writings authored, about, or compiled by Bailey, 1874-1950 (Box 17,19)
    - A Plant At School Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture and Experiment Station of Cornell University Volume 5, No. 5: pages 1-3 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1903 (Box 19, Folder 126)
    - An Appeal To the Teachers of New York State Cornell Home Nature=Study Course Volume 5, No.6: pages 1-11 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1904 (Box 19, Folder 127)
    - What is Agricultural Education? Cornell Countryman Volume 1, No. 7: pages 197-202 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1904 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    - Cornell News Cornell Countryman Volume: page 119, March 1904 (Box 19, Folder 129)
      Notes regarding Bailey Biography
    - Agricultural Education in New York State 24 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1904 (Box 19, Folder 130)
    - Cornell Countryman Volume 1: page 150, April 1904 (Box 19, Folder 131)
    - Dandelion Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture of Cornell University Volume 6, No. 6: page 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1904 (Box 19, Folder 132)
    - Prospectus of the College of Agriculture of Cornell University, 1904-1905 The University Records Series 4, No. 6 Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1904 (Box 19, Folder 133)
    - Lesson I. - The Alfalfa Plant Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture of Cornell University N.S. Volume 1, No. 1: pages 1-2 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1904 (Box 19, Folder 134)
    - Lesson I. - The Pumpkin Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture of Cornell University N.S. Volume 1, No .2: pages 1-2 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1904 (Box 19, Folder 135)
    - The Progress of Fifty Years Proceedings of 50th Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticultural Society pages 1-14 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 136)
      the meeting was held at Rochester,NY on January 25-26, 1905
    - What is Horticulture? Proceedings of American Society of Horticultural Science Author: L. H. Bailey, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 137)
      Read before the Society for the Promotion of Agricultural Science, at its Annual Meeting in 1904; 5 copies
    - [Excerpts of Talk Before Thompson's Island Farm School, Boston] Thompson's Island Beacon Volume 8, No. 10: pages 2-3 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1905 (Box 19, Folder 138)
    - My Old Willow Tree Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture of Cornell University N.S. Volume 1, No. 6: page 7 Author: L. H. Bailey, March 1906 (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - The Mutations Theory of Organic Evolution Science N.S. Volume XXI, No. 536: pages 532-535 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1905 (Box 19, Folder 140)
    - Some Present Problems in Agriculture Science N.S. Volume 21: pages 681-689 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1905 (Box 19, Folder 141)
    - The Brook Junior-Naturalist Monthly, Issued by the College of Agriculture of Cornell University Volume 1, No. 8: page 4 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1905 (Box 19, Folder 142)
    - Our New Agricultural Hall -What It Means Cornell Countryman Volume 2: page 177 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1905 (Box 19, Folder 143)
      Address delivered at the breaking of ground for the "new agricultural hall"
    - What a College Farm Is For Cornell Countryman Volume 3, No. 2: pages 25-28 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1905 (Box 19, Folder 144)
    - Speaker Nixon [necrology] Cornell Countryman Volume 3: pages 39-40 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1905 (Box 19, Folder 145)
    - Tasteful Farm Yards Cornell Reading-Course for Farmers Series 6, No. 27: pages 521-531 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1905 (Box 19, Folder 146)
    - The Prospect For Education In Horticulture Proceedings of 51st Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticultural Society pages 45-51 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1906 (Box 19, Folder 147)
      4 copies
    - To The Winter-Course Student Cornell Countryman Volume 3: pages 111-113 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 1906 (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - How Can a College of Agriculture Keep Close to the Ground? Cornell Countryman Volume 3, No. 9: pages 297-298 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1906 (Box 19, Folder 149)
    - Education By Means of Agriculture The Cornell Era Volume 30, No. 3: pages 105-107 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1906 (Box 19, Folder 150)
    - Prime Causes of Failure in Orcharding Proceedings of 52nd Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticultural Society pages 24-28 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 151)
      the meeting was held at Rochester,NY on January 23-24, 1907
    - The Gentle Art of Killing Fish Letters to The Outlook page 97 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 12, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 152)
    - The Gentle Art of Killing Fish Letters to The Outlook pages 333-334 Author: Edward Breck, February 9, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 152)
    - The Gentle Art of Killing Fish The Outlook pages 79-83 Author: F. Horace McFarland, September 1906 (Box 19, Folder 152)
    - Cyclopedia of American Agriculture - Financial Records Author: L. H. Bailey, 1905-1909 (Box 19, Folder 153)
    - The State and the Farmer Privately printed. Ithaca Journal Press 44 pages Author: L. H. Bailey, June, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 154)
      Presidential address before the Association of American Agricultural Colleges and Experiment Stations at Lansing, Michigan, May 28, 1907; 3 copies
    - A Reverie of Gardens The Outlook pages 267-275 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 155)
      I
    - The Point of View Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume 1, No. 1: pages 1-4 Author: L. H. Bailey, September 1907 (Box 19, Folder 156)
    - Lesson I. No Two Plants are Alike Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume1, No. 2: pages 13-15 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1907 (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - [Abstracts from address at Lansing, Michigan on "The State and the Farmer"] Cornell Countryman Volume 5: pages 25-26 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1907 (Box 19, Folder 158)
      The address in folder 154
    - The Struggle to Live Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume 1, No. 3: pages 33-34 Author: L. H. Bailey, November 1907 (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - Opening Remarks State of New York Department of Agriculture, Report for the Director of Farmer's Institutes and Normal Institutes for the year of 1907 pages 25-30 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 160)
      Before Normal Institute at College of Agriculture, Cornell University, November 25-27, 1907
    - Closing Remarks State of New York Department of Agriculture, Report for the Director of Farmer's Institutes and Normal Institutes for the year of 1907 pages 121-125 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 160)
    - Lesson X. Plants and Animals Become Adapted to the Conditions in Which They Live Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume 1, No. 4: pages 49-50 Author: L. H. Bailey, December 1907 (Box 19, Folder 161)
    - On the Training of Persons to Teach Agriculture in the Public Schools Department of Interior: Bureau of Education Bulletin 1: pages 1-53 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 162)
    - Experiment and Research Cornell Countryman Volume 5: pages 246-248 Author: L. H. Bailey, May 1908 (Box 19, Folder 163)
    - The Graduate School of Agriculture Cornell Countryman Volume 6: pages 7-8 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1908 (Box 19, Folder 164)
    - The College of Agriculture and the State 36 pages Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 19, Folder 165)
      An address delivered at Farmers' Week at Cornell University on February 26, 1909; 3 copies
    - New York State Agricultural Advantages of New York State Issued by the Department of Agriculture of the State of New York Bureau of Statistics Author: Raymond A. Pearson (Box 19, Folder 165)
      A. R. Mann's signature on the front cover
    - Address [on occasion of Mark Vernon Slingerland's death] Cornell Countryman Volume 6: pages 215-216 Author: L. H. Bailey, April 1909 (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - To a Graduating Class, and Others [Abstracts of Remarks at the Assembly on May 20] Cornell Countryman Volume 6: pages 292-293 Author: L. H. Bailey, June 1909 (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - A Point of View On the Scope and Work Of the Irrigation Congress Cornell Countryman Volume 7, No 1: pages 3-6 Author: L. H. Bailey, October 1909 (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - A Statement On the Agricultural Situation in New York State State of New York Department of Agriculture Bulletin 12 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - The Survey-Idea in Country-Life Work Author: L. H. Bailey, July 26,27, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - The Agricultural Situation Cornell Countryman Volume 7: pages 158-161 Author: L. H. Bailey, February, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - A Few Words from Dean Bailey Cornell Countryman Volume 8, No. 1: page 3 Author: L. H. Bailey, October, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Dry Farming Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 10-12 Author: L. H. Bailey, October, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Plea For New County Fair Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 36-38 Author: L. H. Bailey, November, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - William Henry Brewer Cornell Countryman Volume 8: page 69 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - The Farm House Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 82-87 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - The Coming Country Life Epoch National Magazine April: page 82 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Articles about Bailey, 1910-1915 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      4 pieces
    - The Fundamental Question in American Country Life Author: L. H. Bailey, August 17, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Brief Abstracts of the Address to the Student's Association of the New York State College of Agriculture, February 21, 1911 Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 225-228 Author: L. H. Bailey, March, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Farmer's Duty to the New Generation Ithaca Daily Journal Author: L. H. Bailey, March 30, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      Address delivered in front of Agricultural Assembly, Cornell University on February 2, 1911
    - Little Fishes in the Brook Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 279-281 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - The Playground in Rural Communities [Abstract] Cornell Countryman Volume 8: pages 338-340 Author: L. H. Bailey, June, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - A State Program for Rural Betterment Proceedings of the 56th Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticulture Society 56th: pages 40-43 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Blossoms Cornell Rural School Leaflet 5(1): pages 216-217 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - The Playground in Rural Communities The Playground Volume 6; pages 181-185 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - To Students. Greeting Cornell Countryman Volume 9, No. 1: pages 3-4 Author: L. H. Bailey, October, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Report of the Director of the New York State College of Agriculture 1910-11 Author: L. H. Bailey, November, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      Reprint from Official Publications of Cornell University, Vol. 11, No. 18: Nineteenth Annual Report of President Schurman, 1910-11
    - Some Early Agricultural Legislation in New York Proceedings of the 58th Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticulture Society 58th: pages 11-21 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      2 copies; one has pages 11-19, and the other (numbered differently) has all 11pages)
    - A Publication related to the College of Agriculture (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Abstract's of Farmers' Week Address Cornell Countryman Volume 9: pages 225-229 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      Subtitles: The Self-Help Idea in Country-Life Work, The York State Country-Bond, Address to New State Rural Engineering Society, The Educational Position of the Market Gardener, The Need of a Union of Dairy Interests
    - The New Auditorium Cornell Countryman Volume 9, No. 9: pages 283-284 Author: L. H. Bailey, June, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - The Dry-Farming Congress Cornell Countryman Volume 10: pages 60-61 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - What is Horticulture? Cornell Countryman Volume 10, No. 4: page: 89 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - A State Extension Program Cornell Countryman Volume 10: pages 170-171 Author: L. H. Bailey, March, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - The Gouane Palm of Haiti Contributions from The Gray Herbarium No. CLXV Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Liberty Hyde Bailey Author: David Fairchild (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - What is Extension Work? Cornell Countryman Volume 10: pages 250-252 Author: L. H. Bailey, May, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Recommendations and Records for the Meeting of the Agricultural College Council, July 26, 1913 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - The Coming Range in College Work School and Society Volume 109: pages 91-97 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Country Life Teaching The Point of View Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume 7. No. 1: pages 152-156 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      A reprint
    - Manual Training by Means of Agriculture Cornell Rural School Leaflet Volume 7, No. 1: pages 156-158 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Statement of the Forestry Situation Privately Published Address to Governors of the Cornell Club of Rochester, N.Y. Author: L. H. Bailey, December 22, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Dr. L. H. Bailey on the Farm Bureau Movement Farm Bureaus of New York State Circular 3 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 33)
      3 copies; an address before the Erie County Farm Bureau Association at Buffalo, NY; March 17, 1914
    - The Relation of Education to the Country-Life Movement North Carolina High School Bulletin Volume 5, No. 3: pages 106-112 Author: L. H. Bailey, July 1914 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Shall We have an Over-Production of Fruit? Proceedings of the 60th Annual Meeting of the Western New York Horticulture Society 60th: pages 41-50 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 35)
      3 copies
    - The Privilege of the Farm Family Cornell Countryman Volume 11, No. 8: pages 259-260 Author: L. H. Bailey, May, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - The Forthcoming Situation in Agricultural Work Science N.S. Volume XLI, No. 1052: pages 297-306 Author: L. H. Bailey, February 26, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - War and Biology The Journal of Heredity Volume 6, No. 2: pages 51-54 Author: L. H. Bailey, February, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Some Present Needs in Systematic Botany Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society Volume 54, No. 216: pages 58-65 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - The Forthcoming Situation in Agricultural Work - II Science N.S. Volume 43: pages 77-87 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - Rural Manhood Volume 1, No. 6, June, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 41)
    - Living Memorials Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Systematic Work and Evolution Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Needs of New York State Colleges at Cornell University Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      2 copies; one copy has Bailey's signature and stamp
    - Suggestions for the Preparing of Manuscripts for the Rural Books Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - Horticultural Terminology - I American Garden Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - The Philosophy and Practice of Pruning Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 42)
    - The Science-Spirit in a Democracy The Nature-Study Review Volume 12, No. 1: pages 1-10 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 43)
    - Alice McClockey, an Appreciation Cornell Rural School Leaflets Volume 10, No. 1: pages 5-8 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 44)
    - When the Birds Nested The Nature-Study Review Volume 12. No. 6: pages 247-249 Author: L. H. Bailey, September, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - The Brook The Nature-Study Review Volume 13, No: 8: pages 323-324 Author: L. H. Bailey, November, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - Permanent Agriculture and Democracy The American Museum Journal Volume 17, No. 8: pages 537-545 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - Permanent Agriculture and Democracy As Suggested By The Situation in China (Abstract) Proceedings of 38th Annual Meeting, Society for Promotion of Agricultural Science 38th: pages 21-28 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 48)
      the paper was presented before the society at its meeting n Washington DC, November 12, 1917
    - The Modern Systematist Science N.S. Volume 46, No. 1200: pages 623-629 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - The Memories in Weeds The Nature-Study Review Volume 13: pages 378-379 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - Bailey Number Cornell Countryman Volume 11, No. 3, December, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - 1905 Calendar Cornell Countryman (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - The Point of View in China The American Museum Journal Volume 18, No. 4: pages 263-268 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - The Demand for Cheap Food The American Museum Journal Volume 18, no. 7: pages 612-616 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - The Humanistic Element in Education The Nature-Study Review Volume 14, No. 2: pages 43-47 Author: L. H. Bailey, February, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - The Indigen and Cultigen Science N.S. Volume 47: pages 306-308 Author: L. H. Bailey, March, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - A Few Words from President Schurman Cornell Countryman Volume 5, No. 1: pages 3-5 Author: J.G. Schurman, October, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 56)
    - The Impartiality of Research The Proceedings of the American Society for Horticultural Science Volume 16: pages 197-203 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 57)
    - In Appreciation [of A.D. White] Cornell Countryman Volume 16, No. 1: page 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, February, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 58)
    - "Let Us Look Backward in Order that We May Look Ahead" Cornell Countryman Volume 16, No. 5: pages 219-220, 242 Author: L. H. Bailey, June, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 59)
    - Field and Purpose of the American Association of Agricultural Legislation American Association of Agricultural Legislation Bulletin 5 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 60)
    - Retrospect and Prospect The Fruit Belt Combined with Fruits and Gardens page 9 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - A Prospect of American Gardening House and Garden Volume 49: pages 71,162 Author: L. H. Bailey, March, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Current Tendencies in Horticulture [Abstract] The Proceedings of the American Society for Horticultural Science Volume 23: pages 16-18 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 63)
    - The Botanic Garden Idea The Ohio Botanic Garden Society Volume 1, No. 1: pages 1-23 Author: L. H. Bailey, April, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Perils of Over-Emphasis in the Rural Work Proceedings of the Second International Country Life Commission Bulletin 5, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Suggestions Regarding Emphasis Rural America Volume 5, No. 7: pages 7-8 Author: L. H. Bailey, October, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Memories of the College of Agriculture Cornell Countryman Volume 25, No. 3: pages 73-76 Author: L. H. Bailey, December, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 67)
    - Statements on the Systematic Study of Variables The Proceedings for the International Congress of Plant Sciences Volume 2: pages 1427-1433 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 68)
      both the printed and the original copies
    - The Basis of Rural Culture…. Rural America Volume 9, No. 1: page 1 Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 69)
      titleless "article"
    - The Rural Objective Rural America Volume 9, No. 8: page 2, November, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 70)
    - An Interpretation of Point XVII of the Children's Charter White House Conference on Child Health and Protection Author: L. H. Bailey, January, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 71)
    - Fifty Years of Orcharding in America America Fruit Grower Volume 54, No. 5: pages 6-7 Author: L. H. Bailey, May, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 72)
    - Lucy Millington Torreya Volume 39: pages 159-163 Author: L. H. Bailey, November-December, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 73)
      both the printed and the original (hand-written) copies
    - The Rib-Seed Palms in Florida; The Lady Palms Florida Plant Immigrants Occasional Paper no. 7 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 1, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 74)
    - Some Reminiscences of the Development of the American Country Life Movement The Rural Church Institute Mimeograph Series No. 33 Author: L. H. Bailey, August 19, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 75)
    - William Trelease Year Books of The American Philosophical Society pages 420-425 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 76)
    - Horticulture United as I See it Proceedings of the American Horticulture Council for 1946-1948 pages 3-11 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 77)
    - "Horticulture United as I See it" American Horticulture Council, Incorporation Volume 2, No. 2: pages 4-13 Author: L. H. Bailey, October, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 77)
    - photo, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 77)
      L.H. Bailey and Robert Pyle in front of the Universal Symbol of United Horticulture
    - photo, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 77)
      L.H. Bailey, Mrs. Rufus N. Garrett and Arthur G. McKee at the Third Congress, Ithaca
    - Botanical Sciences and Their Applications, Including Agriculture Proceedings from the American Philosophical Society Volume 91, No.1: pages 22-26 Author: L. H. Bailey, February, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 78)
    - Last of the Surviving Mendellers The Journal of Heredity Volume 40: pages 241-242 Author: L. H. Bailey, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 79)
    - Early Days with "The Rural" The Rural New-Yorker Column 100: page 55 Author: L. H. Bailey, January 7, 1950 (Box 17, Folder 80)
    - Permanent Agricultural and Democracy Proceedings of the 38th Annual Meeting, Society for Promotion of Agricultural Sciences pages 21-28 Author: L. H. Bailey (Box 17, Folder 81)
    - Long Island Agronomist Volume 4, No. 6, January 1, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 82)
    - The President-Elect Science N.S. Volume LXIII, No. 1622: pages 120-122 Author: B.E.L., January 29, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 83)
    - Dr. Bailey and His Books Home Acres page 54 Author: J. Horace McFarland, October, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 84)
    - He is Your Garden's Best Friend Better Homes and Gardens Volume 9: pages 40, 68 Author: H. Roy Mosnat, October, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Letter from Bailey to H. Roy Mosnat - typewritten, September 5, 1929 (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Bailey's Home - 6 photos Author: H. Roy Mosnat (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Black walnut tree at the back of the house where Bailey was born (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Apple tree at Bailey's birth place (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - House of Bailey's birth (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - "Bailey Avenue", South Haven; maples planted by Bailey (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Bailey's birthplace - trees and windmill (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - Bailey's birthplace - willow tree (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - 6 other photos of Bailey (Box 17, Folder 85)
    - The Man and His Work Florists' Exchange Volume 77, No. 7: page 9 Author: Peter B. Barnhart, June 13, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 86)
    - A Man and His Workshop Florists' Exchange Volume 77, No. 7: page 9, 28 Author: Janet Ewing Robinson, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 86)
    - Announcement about awarding Bailey with Arthur Hoyt Scott Award of a Gold Medal for 1931 and $1000 (Box 17, Folder 86)
    - Philosopher, Scientist and Gardener The Garden Path Author: Ione M. Klenk (Box 17, Folder 87)